Benjamin Gomez

Full-stack web developer

Austin, Texas | <u>linkedin.com/in/benjamin-a-gomez</u> | <u>github.com/bennygo3</u> (602) 471-5651 | <u>ben3gome@gmail.com</u>

About Me

I am a full-stack developer with experience designing, developing and deploying full-stack applications. I enjoy the process and challenges from initial concept to bringing the application to life. I am also a licensed paramedic that has years of experience working in a highly demanding environment. I look forward to pivoting to the demanding field of software development.

Education

The Coding Bootcamp at the University of Texas at Austin | GPA 4.0 Certificate of Completion from UT Austin - Full Stack Web Developer - March 2022

Austin Community College | GPA 3.3

Level Two certificate in Emergency Medical Services – Paramedic – May 2017 Level One certificate in Emergency Medical Services - EMT Intermediate – May 2016

Horizon High School Phoenix, Arizona | High School Diploma

Highlighted projects

Portfolio | https://bennygo3.github.io/portfolio-react-remix/

My personal portfolio page to showcase some of my front end development skills. I use this space to learn, experiment, and try new languages or techniques. The portfolio section showcases both front end and back end projects that I've worked on.

WhereToWeather | https://bennygo3.github.io/WhereToWeather/

A weather application that utilizes a form input with an API call to return users with a five day weather report for their chosen location. This project was both a challenging and fun learning experience as both styling and graphical elements change based on what the API call returns.

Skills

Programming languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React.js, Express.js, Node.js, jQuery, Bootstrap.

Database technologies: MongoDB, MySQL, JSON.

Other technologies: Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Object Oriented Programming, Database Theory, Command Line and Git.

Work Experience

Paramedic, primary caregiver and medical staff coordinator Private practice | July 2017 - January 2021

I performed at-home healthcare as well as coordinated clinical health care for a high-need VIP patient, working with a broad team of physicians, nurses and other healthcare practitioners. In addition to medical duties, I acted as an executive assistant for my client's significant and prominent business endeavors.

Paramedic, Ambulance | 500+ Clinical Hours

I served as an EMT, EMT Intermediate and a Paramedic for over 500 clinical hours with San Marcos-Hays County EMS, Williamson County EMS and Austin-Travis County EMS, most recently supervised by Captain Jason Beggs for Austin-Travis County. My senior semester required 240 clinical hours on an ambulance which I served at the high-call-volume Medic 2 in Austin- Travis County.

Hospital | EMT Intermediate, 80+ Clinical Hours

I served as an EMT and an EMT Intermediate for over 80 clinical hours with UMC Brackenridge, South Austin Medical Center, Seton Medical Center Austin and Seton Northwest Hospital.

Member services, Barton Creek Resort | May 2013 – June 2017 Guest services, TPC Scottsdale | September 2005-April 2013

I provided high-touch personalized customer-service to each respective golf course's guests while also ensuring the carts, range, and grounds were ready for play.

Awards

2016 St. David's Neal Kocurek ACC scholarship recipient

2005 Arizona 5A varsity football

First Team All-Region, ranked #5 in the state for receiving yards and touchdowns